After 10 Years... He's Back!
Blackadder: Back & Forth is a comedy, history, science
fiction film directed by Paul Weiland.
What was a cunning plan from Lord Edmund Blackadder V to fake a time machine on his gullibly incompetent friends, turns out
to be the real thing and hurls him and his imbecile underling, Baldrick, through the course of human history.
Blackadder, played by Rowan Atkinson.
Baldrick, played by Tony Robinson.
Melchett, played by Stephen Fry.
George, played by Hugh Laurie.
Darling, played by Tim McInnerny.
Queenie, played by Miranda Richardson.
Blackadder: Back & Forth is a 1999 British science fiction comedy short film based on the
BBC period sitcom Blackadder that marks the end of the Blackadder saga.
It was commissioned for showing in the specially built SkyScape cinema erected
southeast of the Millennium Dome on the Greenwich peninsula in South London.
The film follows Lord Edmund Blackadder and his idiotic servant, Baldrick, on a time travel adventure that
brings the characters into contact with several figures significant to British history.
In a 1999 interview, Richard Curtis described it as "an irreverent trek through British history – a time travel adventure story consisting entirely of people who are
either rude or stupid." Rowan Atkinson and Tony Robinson reprised their roles as the series' core characters Blackadder and Baldrick, respectively.
In an interview, Atkinson stated that making a
Blackadder film had always been an ambition.
Joining Atkinson and Robinson are other main cast members from the last three
series, Stephen Fry, Hugh Laurie, Tim McInnerny and Miranda Richardson.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.